<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://clojure-finance.github.io/HKU-TDLEG-website/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>HKU-TDLEG</title><link>https://clojure-finance.github.io/HKU-TDLEG-website/</link><description>This blog serves as documentation for HKU-TDLEG-VOLACK and HKU-TDLEG-financial-signaling-game.</description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 22:40:08 +0800</lastBuildDate><generator>clj-rss</generator><item><guid>https://clojure-finance.github.io/HKU-TDLEG-website/HKU-TDLEG-website/posts-output/2022-01-02-Blog-Post-LIN-Maoran/</guid><link>https://clojure-finance.github.io/HKU-TDLEG-website/HKU-TDLEG-website/posts-output/2022-01-02-Blog-Post-LIN-Maoran/</link><title>Blog Post-LIN Maoran_20220102</title><description>Given that the project is about the signaling effect of firms’ investing time selection, we should also incorporate $t$ to see how it affects investors’ beliefs.The first step is making a more detailed definition about the firms’ quality $\lambda$. Suppose we have the project with the success rate $p$$0$, and failure rate $p$$i$$=1−p$$0$. It is the firm deciding at which date $t \ge 0$ it will invest. The rationale of delaying investment is to do experiment and learn about the project, the longer they need to learn, the lower quality the firms have. According to Vrankić and Skoko (2021), this learning process could be following a Poisson process with $\lambda$ as the intensity of observing a low-quality project in firms’ experiment if $\lambda \ge 0$. Hence, the higher the $\lambda$ is, the lower type the firm belongs to.</description><author>LIN Maoran</author><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://clojure-finance.github.io/HKU-TDLEG-website/HKU-TDLEG-website/posts-output/2021-12-19-Blog-Post-LIN-Maoran/</guid><link>https://clojure-finance.github.io/HKU-TDLEG-website/HKU-TDLEG-website/posts-output/2021-12-19-Blog-Post-LIN-Maoran/</link><title>Blog Post-LIN Maoran_20211219</title><description>Initial ideas about the signaling game model I wish my Clojure to simulate.Suppose for an investment opportunity with payoff $\pi$, there are two types of firms with different profitability $\lambda_h$ and $\lambda_l$.</description><author>LIN Maoran</author><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://clojure-finance.github.io/HKU-TDLEG-website/HKU-TDLEG-website/posts-output/2021-11-21-Blog-Post-WANG-Xizhuo/</guid><link>https://clojure-finance.github.io/HKU-TDLEG-website/HKU-TDLEG-website/posts-output/2021-11-21-Blog-Post-WANG-Xizhuo/</link><title>Data Science in Finance - First Blog</title><description>Work I have done these daysComposing the research proposalThis is the first time for me to write a research proposal. I have included all the contents that I regarded necessary for the audience to know what the
research is doing. However, there are still some parts that need more details.Conducting literature reviewI am reviewing a lot of research that other people have done about hedging strategies. The part that I am most interested in is how they selected data,
how they came up with the strategy, and also how they put their ideas in practice.Learning ClojureI have gone through the Clojure by examples. However, only simple syntax may be not
enough. Therefore, I will explore more sources the learn the language.</description><author>WANG Xizhuo</author><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://clojure-finance.github.io/HKU-TDLEG-website/HKU-TDLEG-website/posts-output/2021-11-21-Blog-Post-LIN-Maoran/</guid><link>https://clojure-finance.github.io/HKU-TDLEG-website/HKU-TDLEG-website/posts-output/2021-11-21-Blog-Post-LIN-Maoran/</link><title>Blog Post-LIN Maoran_20211121</title><description>Some initiatives about my project: My project would like to investigate whether the firms’ timing in investment and operation could be effectively used as a signal to evaluate their qualities. Without clear pictures about firms’ real quality, investors and financial institutions would need signals to facilitate their financing decisions. It would be assumed by investors that firms with lower quality would choose to delay their investment and operation while high-performance companies would have earlier implementation of their decisions. Hence, as a strategy to fool outsiders, the low-quality firms would have the signal incentive to mimic the investment timeline as high-quality firms to extract bonus in their loans, while the high- type firm would try to distinct their identities by accelerating their investments and operations. We would like to explore how Clojure could help us build a signaling game model to evaluate the effectiveness of this timing strategy. We would then apply this model with empirical panel data collected by a World Banks’ Enterprise level survey on Chinese enterprises to test its validity.</description><author>LIN Maoran</author><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>